Guide to the Investment Office, Yale University, Records Concerning Ethical Investments
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Investment Office, Yale University, records concerning ethical investments
1977-1994
RU 296
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
18
(18 boxes)
The records consist of reports and subject files of the Yale Investment Office concerning ethical investing, particulary in South Africa and tobacco companies.
Yale University. Investment Office
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 5-D (YRG 5-D), Investment and insurance records of Yale University.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of reports and subject files of the Yale Investment Office concerning ethical investing, particulary in South Africa and tobacco companies.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Investments -- Moral and ethical aspects; Investments; Universities and colleges -- Finance; Yale University -- Finance; Yale University. Investment Office; Yale University. Office of Finance and Administration
- Records of investment policy for various responsibility issues primarily divestment in South Aftica, 1972-1994; Accession 1997-A-043
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until January 1, 2044
  - General files
    - "Beyond Divestment: the Moral University": speech to AACHE, 1986 Mar 13 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Public statements on South African investments, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Committees
    - Alumni Committee on Investor Responsibility (ACIR)
      - Agenda memoranda campus correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence
        - General
          - 1976 (Box 2, Folder 8)
          - 1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
          - 1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
          - 1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
          - 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 11a)
          - 1980 (Box 2, Folder 12)
          - 1981 (Box 2, Folder 13)
          - 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 13a)
          - 1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
          - 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
          - 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 17)
          - 1992 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Fact-finding trip to South Africa, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Harvard report, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Letters
        - Drafts, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 39)
        - Letters, correspondence and memoranda, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 39a)
        - Letters to Richard C. Levin re: South Africa, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - Meetings
      - Notes and correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Policy Recomendations, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Policy guidelines summary, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 7a)
      - Presidential letters of invitation, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - South Africa Ivy Group proposal, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - Summary of votes, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Committee on the use of Hewitt Quadrangle, correspondence-re: Winnie Mandela City, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Records concerning investment responsibility, 1986-1988; Accession 1998-A-001
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2038.
  - South Africa Materials
    - Cornell University Research Report on South Africa, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Cornell University Research Report on South Africa, second addendum, 1985 (Box 1)
  - ADVISORY COMMITTEE FOR INVESTOR RESPONSIBILITIES
    - Policy - guidelines summary, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Presidential letters of invitation, 1993 -94 (Box 3)
    - Levin Letter, 1994 (Box 4)
- Corporation Committee of the whole meeting information packet on investor responsibility regarding tobacco, 1992; Accession 2001-A-097
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2042.